Subindex build by Linnet http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli »ðÄñ×ÖÄ»ºÏ²¢Æ÷SubindexV0.5 Created time 10.04.22 22:50:46
Subindex build by Linnet http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli 火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5 Created time 10.04.22 22:50:40
Air Force One
空军一号
Check, Head count, Head count, Two, Three
检查人数 二 三
Four, Five
四 五
Six
六
Demo set
安装炸药
Let's move
走吧
Clear
安全
Low Boy, this is Black Cat
小子 这是黑猫
ETA Romeo, L-Z-one-niner
19秒后回到屋顶
We are hot, Copy
我们马上赶来
Come on, Get out there! Go, go!
快出去
Come on
快点
Get in!
上去
Cover! I'm on the roof!
屋顶上有敌人
Go!
起飞
This is Low Boy, Package is wrapped
这是小子 任务完成
Ladies and gentlemen
各位贵宾
three weeks ago, Russian and American special forces
三个礼拜前 美俄特种部队
apprehended the self-proclaimed leader of Kazakhstan, General Ivan Radek
逮捕自封为哈萨克斯坦领袖的 伊凡・拉狄克将军
His nuclear arsenal could have brought the world
他的核子武器 可能再造成新的冷战
But thanks to the support of one of the world's greatest leaders
一名伟大的世界领袖 仗义相助
Radek is now in prison
让拉狄克锒铛入狱
Today we are honoring this brave man
今晚我们向这位勇士致敬
Ladies and gentlemen, my friend
各位贵宾吾友...
the president of the United States of America
...美国总统
The dead remember our indifference, The dead remember our silence
死者永记 我们沉默无语
I came here tonight to be congratulated
这原本是场庆功宴
But today when I visited the Red Cross camps
可是当我探访红十会难民营
overwhelmed by the flood of refugees, fleeing from the horror of Kazakhstan
目睹逃离暴政的哈萨克斯坦人民
I realized I don't deserve to be congratulated, none of us do
我知道我们没有资格庆功 谁都没有资格
- What's he doing? - That's not the speech
- 他在干什么? - 这不是演讲稿
The truth is
事实是
we acted too late
我们为时已晚
Only when our own national security was threatened did we act
我们等到自己的国家安全 受到威胁才行动
Radek's regime murdered over 200, 000 men, women and children
拉狄克政权屠杀 二十万名男女老幼
and we watched it on TV, We let it happen, People were being slaughtered
我们看着电视 袖手旁观
for over a year
大屠杀进行一年有余
We issued economic sanctions and hid behind the rhetoric of diplomacy
我们却只实施经济制裁 拿外交辞令当藉口
How dare we? The dead remember
真不应该 死者不会原谅我们
Real peace, is not just the absence of conflict, it's the presence of justice
真正的和平不是避免冲突 而是伸张正义
Tonight I come to you with a pledge to change America's policy
今晚我誓言改变美国政策
Never again, will I allow our political self - interest
我绝不再让政治利益
to deter us from doing what we know to be morally right
阻止我们捍卫道德的勇气
Atrocity and terror are not political weapons
暴行和屠杀绝非政治手段
And to those who would use them
至于恐怖份子
your day is over
你们的死期到了
We will never negotiate
我们不再谈判
We will no longer tolerate and we will no longer be afraid
我们不再姑息养奸 担心害怕
It's your turn to be afraid
你们才该害怕
The Russian was a nice touch
那两句俄语是神来之笔
Tell my mother, She wanted me to study French
我母亲本来要我学法语
Do you know what you committed us to?
你知道你得说话算话
I know exactly what I committed us to
我当然知道
Gentlemen, welcome to "Air Force One,"
各位欢迎搭乘空军一号
Please present your equipment for inspection
我们要检查你们的器材
We were just inspected at the gate
刚才检查过了
This plane carries the president of the United States
这是美国总统的专机
I understand, I'm terribly sorry
我了解抱歉
Please place your thumb on the ID pad
请把拇指按在辨识板上
Access cleared
准许进入
Hello, I'm Melanie Mitchell, deputy press secretary
你们好 我是副公关秘书梅兰妮・米契
- I'll be taking you in from here, - Oh, Miss Mitchell
- 我会带你们上机 - 米契小姐
It is so nice to finally meet you in person
很高兴终于和你见面
The president and I were delighted we could accommodate your news crew
我们都很高兴能接待你们
So, if you boys are all cleared?
你们都获准上机
The president's on a very tight schedule so this is how it works
总统很忙请你们配合
During the flight, two members of your crew
待会只有两人
will be allowed outside the press area for filming
能到机上拍摄
You'll get exactly 10 minutes with the president, 20 with the crew
总统有十分钟 机员二十分钟
Gary, the president is ready to take Congress on
总统要和国会抗争到底
He's not gonna kiss their ass for each vote
他不会为了选票妥协
Let them vote us down and stand on their record
他们投票反对就得自承后果
Yeah, I'm with him now, I'll call you from the plane
他在这里 待会再说
- What did they say about the speech? - Your speech is leading the news
- 他们有何反应? - 你的演讲是头条新闻
They're calling it the "Be Afraid" speech
记者都说那是"死期"演讲
Good
很好
With all due respect, next time you want to make
下次 你要改变政策
a major policy departure, you might want to discuss it
请你先和
with your national security advisor first
国家安全顾问商量
- We did discuss it, Jack, - We discussed it
- 我们谈过 - 私下谈过
in private, which is where I thought it would remain
在私下 我以为只是如此
Now it's public, Now it's policy
现在这是公开的政策
Get behind it
你一定要支持
The allies are going to be very upset they weren't consulted about this
你没事先照会 盟国会很生气
It might come back and bite us in the ass in November
可能会影响十一月大选
It's the right thing to do, You know it
这么做是对的 你们都知道
There goes the neighborhood
这下完了
If you'd like, we have time for a quick tour
我有时间 带你们参观一下
- We'd be delighted, - Good
- 那就太好了 - 很好
Andrei, Boris
安德烈 鲍里斯
Follow me
请跟我来
Ahead of this staff cabin is Secret Service, Right here
这里是特勤人员驻守的区域
Never try to go past them without an escort or you'll be very sorry
没有人陪同千万别硬闯
- Hello - Hi
- 你好 - 嗨
Thanks for the warning
谢谢你的警告
Here we have our in-flight offices
这里是机上的办公室
A lot of the plane's features are classified
这些设备很机密
But I can tell you it's bullet-resistant
全都能防弹
and it's even protected against the pulse of a nuclear blast
甚至能抵挡核爆的威力
I'm not sure that's very comforting
这真能让人安心
Upstairs is the cockpit along with the most advanced communications center
最先进的通讯中心
on or above the face of the earth
上面是驾驶舱 还有地面空中
We could run the whole country from here
足以治理一个国家
Or even a war if we had to
或是发动战争
Just last week, the president called the shuttle astronauts from there
上礼拜总统就在这儿 和太空人通话
The president's arriving, They should take their seats
总统即将抵达 请他们回座
Right away
马上回去
I'll get out of here and let you all get some sleep
我就让各位休息吧
- Mr.President, welcome aboard, - Hey, Danny, How are you?
- 总统先生 欢迎登机 - 丹尼 你好
Mr.President!
总统先生
Change in plan, Danny, Let's go to Barbados
改变行程 咱们到巴贝多去
Anything you want, You're the president
您想去就去 您是总统
Boy, I wish
是真的就好
- Mr.President, - Mr.Gibbs, where's my bunch?
- 总统先生 - 她们人呢?
Ballet ran late, They'll be here in five minutes
芭蕾舞刚结束她们正赶来
- Lewis, you tape the game? - It was a real squeaker, sir
- 球赛录了吗? - 真是精采刺激
Don't brief me on it, I wanted to watch it, for Christ's sake
别向我简报我还想看呢
We'll be underway in about 30 minutes, sir
半小时后就起飞
Mr.President
总统先生
- Could you put the game on now? - Yeah, Jack?
- 请你放球赛吧 - 什么事?
The Iraqis have mobilized two armored brigades toward. . .
伊拉克出动两辆装甲车...
Just got it, Give me 15 minutes, Get the guys together
我知道等我十五分钟 召集大家开会
"Repel them, Make them relinquish the ball,"
看过球赛吗? 打得你死我活
- Did you hear about Notre Dame? - Don't, Don't tell me the score
- 你听过圣母院吗? - 别把比数告诉我
- Great game, - Mr.President
- 球赛好精采 - 总统先生
We need to strategize, smooth some things out politically
我们得向盟国解释...
- What was that? - It's not so important
- 那是什么? - 不重要
- Damage control, What if. . . - Give me a minute alone
- ...及时补救 - 让我静一下
What if a "high-ranking White House official". . .
也许应该让政府官员...
Just give me a few moments alone
让我静一下
A "high - ranking official" were to qualify what you said last night?
...让政府官员缓和你的措辞
Drop it, Do yourself a favor
别再说了这是政策
It's policy, Drop it
你再说就改搭别的班机
I told them you'd give them a sound bite about life in the White House
俄国记者想知道 你在白宫的生活
There is no life in the White House
白宫没有生活可言
You said it, The president needs some time alone
说得好 总统想静一下
14-13 Michigan!
十四比十三密歇根大学赢
All right, Mr.President!
棒呆了总统先生
That wasn't you napping during the performance, was it, Tom?
你看芭蕾舞时没打瞌睡吧?
No, ma'am, It was very enjoyable
没有挺好看的
Alice, you can finish it on the plane, Let's not keep your father waiting
走吧待会再看 别让你爸等太久
Try and smile, sweetheart, Okay?
试着笑一笑好吗?
- Alice, one picture, please! - Thank you very much
- 爱丽丝一张相片! - 非常感谢你
Great, something from Tom
好伟大出自汤姆之手
Shh, Daddy's asleep
嘘爹地睡着了
How was the ballet?
芭蕾舞好看吗?
It was great!
棒呆了
You trying to kill me? Wait it really good? Did you enjoy it?
你想害死我吗? 别这样
Did you love it? Men in tights? Did you hear my speech?
男人穿紧身裤有什么好看? 听到我的演讲吗?
- Yeah, - Yeah?
- 听到了 - 怎样?
- You're gonna get yourself reelected, - That's what I keep telling them
- 你会获得连任 - 我一直跟他们这么说
This is the aircraft commander, We'll take to the runway in a moment
这是机长 我们将一瞬间离开跑道
- Are you guys comfortable? - Yes, very
- 你们还好吧? - 很好
This is the information used in the VIP
这是贵宾用的资料
thank you
谢谢你
You're welcome
不客气
Pass interference, That's cheating
妨碍接球他犯规
- Only if they get caught, - Dad!
- 被逮到才算 - 爸
The way of the world, kiddo
这是现实世界
Why didn't you take me with you when you went to the refugee camp today?
你今天去难民营 为什么不带我去?
For one thing, it's not 100 percent secure
那里不是百分之百安全 你还小不必看这种事
Come on, Dad, It's not like I don't see it on the news
哦爹地我在新闻中都看到过
It's different on the news
那和新闻不同
All I'm saying is I'm ready for things you don't think I'm ready for
我能接受的事比你想像的多
Maybe I'm not ready
也许我不能接受
I'm 12 years old, Dad!
我十二岁了
In the caveman days, I'd be having children of my own
十二岁的原始人都能生孩子
That's what we call progress, You're missing the best part of the game
我们是文明人 快看球赛
God!
真是的
We're so looking forward to seeing you
我们很期待和你见面
- She is so anxious to grow up, - I know, She's. . .
- 她等不及想长大 - 我知道
Yes, the both of us, Okay, Bye, bye
我们都是好再见
Well, she couldn't stay your little girl forever, Jim
你的小女儿不能永远长不大
I was hoping it would last till she was 14 or 15
我只希望等到十四或十五岁
Or 50
或是五十岁
They hated your speech, didn't they?
他们不喜欢你的演讲
They're afraid we won't have the guts to back it up
他们怕我们不能言出必行
And, then, if we do, it'll be political suicide
就算能 也会毁了政治前途
Remember our first campaign?
记得你第一次竞选吗?
- In the House? - Yeah
- 竞选众议员? - 对我们一起坐车
- Downstate, driving around with. . . - Who was that kid, our volunteer?
- 在州里的南部驾驶的 - 谁是孩子的时候我们的志愿者?
- Henry, - Henry with the convertible
- 亨利 - 亨利和敞蓬车
- With the broken top, - And the snow coming in
- 开着那辆破敞蓬车 - 大雪灌进车里
We were the only three people who thought you could win that
只有我们三个认为你能赢
You didn't give a damn, You knew what needed to be done and you did it
你不为名利 只为信念努力
And you spoke from your heart, That's what I heard tonight
你的话发自内心 今晚也一样
Well, it felt good
感觉很好
I'll bet it did
那是一定的
Sorry to interrupt, Everybody's assembled, sir
不好意思大家都到齐了 长官
United States "Air Force One,"
美国空军一号
It is an honor to clear you for immediate takeoff on runway 2- 5
25跑道可供你们马上起飞
"Air Force One" cleared for takeoff
空军一号可以起飞
Thank you for your hospitality, Moscow
谢谢莫斯科的热情接待
In Moscow tonight, President Marshall defended
马歇尔总统为他对拉狄克展开
the military action against the Radek regime
军事行动打击拉杰克制度
an act the administration had been calling a one-time intervention
所谓的 "武装干预"进行辩护
But in a rare display of emotion
他表现出罕见的情绪
the president alluded to a change in US foreign policy when he stated
指出他将改变美国外交政策
that America will no longer tolerate any terrorist government
他说美国 将不再容忍恐怖行动
These are two of Saddam Hussein's Republican Guard brigades
两旅萨达姆・侯赛因的共和国卫队向北移动
He knows we're watching, knows we'll retaliate
侯赛因明知我们会报复 为什么还这么做?
Why the hell is he sending tanks to the border?
为什么是他的地狱派遣坦克边界
Could be a response to your speech, Mr.President
也许是因为你的演讲
- Maybe he's got a son-in-law up there, - Very funny
- 也许他在北边有女婿 - 不好笑
I think there's one or two he hasn't shot yet
他还剩两个没除掉
What does State have to say?
国务院怎么说?
The Iraqi ambassador is claiming it's just an exercise
伊拉克大使说那只是演习
Let's not waste more time, Send the "Nimitz" back in
别浪费时间 派尼米兹号回去
- Gibbs, - Guys
- 吉布 - 大伙
- Sleeping on the job? - No, sir
- 你在偷懒吗? - 没有
Hey, guys, This is a special report of the Panel in Miami
这是迈阿密特勤小组的报告
- Take a look at them, - Thank you
- 你们看一看 - 谢谢
Steward, there's smoke in the cabin
有烟 机舱在冒烟
Everybody move to the back of the plane, Now! Please!
大家请到机尾
Smoke! Notify the cockpit!
有烟通知驾驶舱 趴下来
Mr.President, stay back
总统先生 请退后
Everybody down!
大家趴下
Code red! We have a code red! I repeat, Shots fired on board
紧急状况 我重复
Code red acknowledged, Lock that door now
知道了关上门
Flight control, this is "Air Force One" declaring emergency
这是空军一号 发生紧急状况
Cover us!
掩护我们
Stay back
别过去
Move up! I'll cover you
上吧我掩护你
Go! Go!
快点快点
- What's going on? - Shots fired, sir
- 怎么回事? - 有人开枪
- What about my family? - We're handling it, sir
- 我的妻女呢? - 我们会处理长官
Boy Scout coming out! Cover!
童子军出来了
- Give us cover! - Daddy?
- 给我拉支持 - 爹地
Alice, get back!
爱丽丝 退后
Daddy
爹地
Alice, get down!
爱丽丝快趴下
- Take him around here, - Get down
- 把他带过来 - 趴下
This is "Air Force One,"We are code red, Shots fired on board
塔台 空军一号紧急状况
Request emergency assistance, ETA 15 minutes
需要协助 15分钟后到达
Acknowledged, We are scrambling our fighters, Emergency equipment
空军一号 知道了 我们会准备
will be standing by
紧急支援
Get him to the escape pod!
快进逃生舱
Boy Scout is headed to the vault
童子军前往逃生舱
The football! The football!
足球核弹发射密码
Get him around here, Get him down to the pod!
把他带下来 快进逃生舱
Don't move!
别动
Go to the President
去找总统
- They're on us, - Where's my family?
- 他们跟来了 - 我的家人呢?
- Get in the pod, sir, Get in! - What about my family?
- 进去 长官 - 我的家人呢?
"Air Force One," landing runway 0- 9, I repeat, runway 0- 9
空军一号请使用09跑道 重复09跑道
Roger, Turning to heading 1- 8- 5, Descending to 5, 000 feet
收到 方向是185 高度5千尺
Quickly, he ran into the escape capsule
快点他跑进逃生舱
Ramstein, this is "Air Force One,"
塔台这是空军一号 逃生舱已发射
Emergency pod has been deployed, I repeat
重复逃生舱已发射
- The emergency pod has been deployed, - Ramstein tower, acknowledge
- 逃生舱已发射 - 塔台确认
We are picking up the homing beacon and deploying search and rescue
收到讯号已派出搜救小组
- Is the locking ready to look at? - Just about, sir
- 诺维将军到了吗? - 到了
- Has General Northwood arrived? - Yes, he has
- 其他人都通知了吗? - 都通知了
- Give me an update, - Madam Vice President, this way
- 情况如何? - 这里请副总统
- We'll avoid the press, - Is the president secure?
- 我们得避开记者 - 找到总统吗?
Not yet, The recovery team will have him very soon
还没有搜救小组会找到他
"Air Force One", this is Halo Flight Lead, you are under escort
空军一号 这是光环分队
All airspace has been cleared, Alert force has been mobilized
战机进行护卫领空已安全 全体紧急动员
- Is everyone here? - We're working on it
- 人都到了吗? - 就快到了
How did this happen? How did they get "Air Force One"?
他们怎么可能 挟持空军一号?
Gentlemen, Mr.Secretary
各位部长先生
Ramstein tower, we are at ten mile. . . Final coming in red hot
塔台 距离十哩 情况危急
Roger,"Air Force One," Wind is 0-niner-0 at 12, You are clear to land
收到空军一号 风速12节你可以降落
They landed
他们要降落
Get down! Now!
给我趴下来
Open the door!
快开门快开门
Open! Open the door!
快开门快打开来
No matter what happens, we land this aircraft, Is that understood?
无论如何都得降落 明白吗?
Come on, Flaps 30
快点 尾翼30度
Flaps 30
尾翼30度
- No! - Get the fuck in the air!
- 一降落就完了 - 回到空中
Now! Take this plane up!
快点 快升空
Up! Up!
升空快升空
Take it up!
升空
Get this plane back in the air now or you die
给我升空你在干嘛?
Get up now!
快升空
No! Jesus!
不老天
Contact those F-15s
快通知F15战机
I want them to keep "Air Force One" in visual contact
要他们一直盯着空军一号
- What are our airborne scenarios? - There are no airborne scenarios
- 劫机的紧急程序是什么? - 根本就没有
Then we'd better start generating them, They better be good and better work
我们最好快想办法 而且一定得成功
How long can they stay up there with the fuel they have?
他们还能飞多久?
- That's a question of airspeed, wind, - Altitude
- 这要看速度和风向 - 还有高度
We need an "Air Force One" pilot, Any educated guesses where they might go?
快把飞行员找来 他们可能飞去哪儿?
- Iraq, Libya, Algeria, - Those are guesses, but not educated
- 伊拉克 利比亚... - 这只是猜测没有根据
Notify our allies, We'll need secure airspace
通知盟国清出领空 别透露消息
- Can we keep that under wraps? - We'll do our best
- 我们能保持联系吗? - 我尽量试
Try and relax, Kathryn, I'm in charge here
放轻松凯瑟琳在我掌控中
I don't know, It seems to me they're in charge
不晓得 似乎是他们在掌控
We have to go home
我们要回家了
- Don't hurt me, - Go
- 不要伤害我 - 走
Go
走
Where the President?
总统呢?
He is not the plane
他不在机上
He ran into the cabin to escape to escape
他跑进逃生舱逃走
Moscow police found six members of a Russian TV news crew murdered
莫斯科警方 发现六名俄国电视记者遇害
They are allowed to board Air Force One
他们获准登上空军一号
My God
天哪
Tell me it's not that easy
别跟我说有这么简单
No, You would have to generate fake ID photos, Fingerprints
他们得伪造身份证 指纹
Could be with help from Moscow
可能得到俄国政府协助
How would they get weapons on board?
他们怎么拿到武器?
There's no way to get weapons on board "Air Force One," It's impossible
机上不可能拿到武器 不可能
There are enough weapons on board to take Panama, but who has access to them?
他们手上有武器 从哪儿来的?
You think someone on the plane helped them?
机上有人帮助他们吗?
What if somebody did and they're still on the plane?
如果是真的 这个人还在机上
Who do they trust up there? Who do we trust?
他们能相信谁? 我们该相信谁?
Madam Vice President, Mr.Secretary
副总统 部长先生
All compromised nuclear launch codes have been cancelled, New codes are active
核弹发射密码取消 全都换成新的
Ramstein, the president's escape pod has been located
塔台 我们找到总统的逃生舱
We're honing in at 2-8-5 degrees
讯号在285度
There it is, Ramstein, we have a strong signal
在那儿 讯号很强
ETA, two minutes
估计两分钟后赶到
Where is the wife and daughter?
他的妻女呢?
Get out
让开
Where is my husband?
我先生呢?
He had fled, The coward chose to save himself
他开溜了 这懦夫只顾着逃命
But one can always strike a bargain
不过我有谈判的筹码
You listen to me
你给我听好
I don't know who you are or what you want
不管你是谁有何目的
but you will never get it
你都不能得逞
He will not negotiate
他不会和你谈判
Really?
是吗?
His wife, His daughter
他的妻子 女儿在我手上
A man could not live with himself
一个男人绝不会抛下妻女
And it would be such bad politics
何况这会影响他的政治前途
I think he'll negotiate
我看他一定会谈判
The escape pod is visually acquired
我们看到逃生舱
Location of Ramstein is 2-8-4 degrees, Twelve miles out
方位284度 距离瑞姆斯丹十二英哩
Recover all weapons to the
武器全都收回来了
Renevski, and then search again
尼夫斯基 再查一次
You round the first guard
你轮第一班看守
I went to search the following
我去搜下面
Okay
好了
It's "Air Force One," They want to talk to the vice president
是空军一号 他们找副总统
Hello, Can you hear me?
喂? 你听得到吗?
This is the vice president of the United States, To whom am I speaking?
我是美国副总统 你是哪位?
This is the person who controls "Air Force One,"
我是控制空军一号的人
The world's most secure aircraft
世上最安全的飞机
What is it that you want?
你要什么?
We'll get to that
待会再说
- I want to speak to the First Lady, - No
- 我想和第一夫人谈话 - 不行为什么?
I would like to determine the safety of their
我要确定她们的安全
The president is safe, But then you must know that
总统很安全你们应该知道
He ran from here like a whipped dog
他像条狗夹着尾巴逃走
I'm sure you can't wait for him to get back to making the decisions
你一定急着等他回去指挥
so you can stop sweating through that silk blouse of yours
你就不必直冒冷汗 弄湿丝衬衫
What is the condition of the people on board?
机上乘客情况如何?
Some are dead
死了一些人
What are your intentions?
你有什么目的?
What arrogance to think you could ever understand my intentions
你怎么能了解我的目的?
I want to understand what it is that you want
我想知道你要什么
What do I want?
我要什么?
When Mother Russia becomes one great nation again
当伟大的苏俄祖国再度统一
when the capitalists are dragged from the Kremlin
当资本家被拖到街上枪毙
when our enemies run and hide in fear at the mention of our name
当敌人听到俄国威名 逃之夭夭
and America begs our forgiveness
当美国乞求我们原谅
on that great day of deliverance
当这伟大的日子来临
you will know what I want
你就知道我要什么
We can give you a forum for your grievances, We can contact the Russian government
我能让你提出申诉 我能联络俄国政府
But you must understand that it will take some time
不过你要了解 这得花点时间
Really? When you talk to the president
是吗? 请你转告总统
you might remind him that I am holding his wife, his daughter, his chief of staff, his national security advisor
你告诉他 他的妻女 幕僚长 国家安全顾问
his classified papers and his baseball glove
机密文件和棒球手套 全在我手上
If he wants them back, he will prevail upon the puppet regime in Moscow
他想要拿回去 就得逼莫斯科的傀儡政府
to release General Radek
释放拉狄克将军
Fifty for one, It's a good deal
五十人换一人很划算
How's your blouse?
你还在冒冷汗吗?
What assurances do I have that you'll keep your word?
我怎么知道你会说话算话?
I'll wait for confirmation that General Radek has been released
我要确定拉狄克将军 被安全释放
Until then
在他被释放之前
I will execute a hostage every half an hour
每半小时我就处决一名人质
You have my word
我说话算话
You must understand that we. . . Hello?
你要了解我们...喂?
They're off!
切断了
Damn it! Nobody does this, to the United States
该死谁都不能欺负美国
The president will get back his glove and play catch with this guy's balls
总统会讨回他的手套 要这砘锖每
We can't do anything in half an hour, We need more time
半小时来不及 我们需要更多时间
He's a zealot, Tough to negotiate with, All you can do is wear them down
他是狂热份子 不会跟你谈判 我们只能跟他磨下去
Mr.Secretary!
部长先生
We found the escape pod, It's empty
找到逃生舱上面没有人
So where's the president?
总统在哪里?
I think we have to acknowledge the possibility, that the president may be dead
我们必须面对 总统已经丧命的可能
Why do they not say?
他们为何不说?
Diversion, Try to buy some time
引开注意拖延时间
It could have happened in a cross fire
他可能遭枪击
and they're afraid we'll retaliate
他们怕我们会报复
Damn right, we'll retaliate, We'll release Radek into the atmosphere
我们当然会报复 我们要让拉狄克粉身碎骨
It doesn't add up, That terrorist knew we'd recover the pod in short order
这没有道理 对方知道有逃生舱
He expected that we'd be talking to Marshall
我们会找到马歇尔
Let's not bury him yet, He could still be alive in that plane
先别乱猜他可能还在机上
Let's not forget this president is a Medal of Honor winner
别忘了总统得过英勇奖章
In Vietnam, he flew more helicopter missions than any man in my command
他在越战中 多次驾直升机救人
He knows how to fight
他知道如何格斗
Then he's taking a terrible chance with his life
那么他就冒很大的生命危险
The element of surprise is a formidable advantage in combat
出其不意是战斗的优势
If he's up there, he's the best chance that we have
他若在机上 就是我们唯一的希望
That pod was designed for a reason, General
逃生舱有它的作用
He has no right to take chances with his life
他不能冒生命危险
Everything is Nothing
一切都没问题
What does the psych profile say? How far will he go?
他档案有什么资料? 他是什么人?
He's a Radek loyalist
他是拉狄克的忠臣
That tells us all we need to know, doesn't it?
没什么好问的
He'll see this thing through to the last hostage or his own death
他愿意杀死每一个人质 甚至牺牲自己的性命
Release this bastard and Central Asia will go up in flames!
放走拉狄克 中亚细亚就会战火连连
I'm aware of that
我知道
Bring back the old Soviet empire under a flag of genocide?
让他以大屠杀为名 恢复旧俄帝国?
Radek with a nuclear arsenal?
让拉狄克拥有核弹?
I hate to say this, but 50 people
牺牲五十条人命
is a small price to pay to stop that from happening
就能避免此事
Even if one of them is the president?
其中一人可能是总统
The presidency is bigger than any man, Didn't they teach you that at Yale?
总统职位比人命重要 耶鲁大学没教吗?
Can't we release him today and pick up the pieces tomorrow?
难道不能先放了他 然后再逮捕他?
We caught him before, we'll catch him again
我们又不是没逮过他
If Petrov releases Radek, his government will fall
放了他 帕特罗夫的政府就会垮台
I promise you that, Then who's gonna stand up to Radek?
我保证没人敢反对拉狄克
You go to catch him again, you'll find him in Moscow
他一定会夺权 别想再逮到他
With respect, Mr.Secretary
请恕我直言部长先生
we don't need more dramatics, we need options
请你别危言耸听 我们需要别的选择
- It's not an option, - We need a decision
- 我们别无选择 - 你要做出决定
It's not her decision
她不能决定
This is a military situation, I'm the secretary of defense
这是军事状况 我是国防部长
Check your regs, In the absence of the president, the buck stops here
尽管去查 总统不在由我作主
Get the attorney general with a copy of the Constitution
请司法部长把宪法带来 我们只剩...
We have. . . Oh, my God! Nineteen minutes
我的天19分钟
I'm going to consult with President Petrov
我得和帕特罗夫总统商量
Madam Vice President, I'm sorry, I cannot release him
副总统很抱歉 我不能释放他
We would train, all our military might against this one target
我们会出动所有军力逮捕他
He wouldn't stay at large for long
我向你保证他逃不了的
Maybe so, But millions of lives are hanging in the balance
也许吧 不过事关数百万条人命
I am trying to save a nation!
我正试着挽救国家
As am I
我也是
No nation can survive the loss, nor soon replace, a great leader
国家不能承受 失去伟大领袖的打击
Let us be pragmatic, Fifty lives means nothing
恕我直言
in the grand scheme, What life is not 50
为了顾全大局 五十条人命不算什么
Let me be equally pragmatic
那么请你也恕我直言
Our president took a great risk to come to your aid
总统不顾反对朝野两党
against strong opposition in both parties and among our allies
和盟国的反对 冒险帮助你
It would be politically impossible to do so again
他以后不可能再帮你
If it meant saving his life, I would gladly do it
我很乐意救他一命
But I would have to know for sure, And you cannot tell me he's alive, can you?
可是你不能确定他还活着
No, Mr.President, I cannot
没错总统先生
Then there is nothing I can do, I am truly sorry, Good-bye
那么我也无能为力 很抱歉再见
Okay, Walter, you and your generals get to work
好吧沃尔特 命令军方想办法解救人质
He told me five years fighting in Afghanistan
他跟我在阿富汗奋战五年
To find the murderer, or else you die
找出凶手否则你们就没命
Okay, they can't keep the plane in the air indefinitely
他们不能一直飞下去
There are only four possible landing sites in Kazakhstan
拉狄克在哈萨克斯坦
that are still controlled by Radek's forces
仍然掌控四座机场
We have to go in and take all of them, Can we do it?
我们得全部占领行吗?
I'd rather take my chances in the air
我宁愿在空中冒险
I just looked at the airborne scenarios, They're no good
空中救援没有用
- Can we do this? - In the time we have? Messy
- 这办法可行吗? - 在这么短的时间里? 很困难
Three more minutes before they execute the first hostage
再过三分钟 他就会杀第一名人质
You'll have to buy us more time
尽量争取时间
All right
时间到了
The telephone from a conference room
把电话接到会议室
You both, come here
你们两个给我过来
Now!
快点
They will transfer the call here
他们会把电话接过来
let's just wait
咱们等吧
Excuse me
对不起
Sir, if you will permit me, I am the national security advisor
先生我是国家安全顾问
I'm the man the president would be listening to
总统都听我的意见
I believe you are negotiating right now with the vice president
我相信你正和副总统谈判
In our system, the vice president is like the queen of England
可惜在美国 副总统就像英国女王
She can't even get airline tickets without talking
她想买张机票 都得找我这种人
to somebody like me; therefore, let me speak to the White House
让我和白宫说话
I promise you, I'm the one person who can make this all work out
我保证我能解决这件事
Has he been released?
他被释放了吗?
I've contacted the Russian government, We've set things in motion
我联络过俄国政府 事情有进展
But at this point, we have to be realistic, It's going to take more time
不过 你要了解 这得花时间
More time?
时间?
Your national security adviser, was executed
你的国家安全顾问被处死
He's a very good negotiator, He bought you another half hour
他很会谈判 他争取到半小时
Mrs, Marshall, Alice
总统夫人 爱丽丝
If you please, come with me
请跟我来
That's the first time you ever seen a man killed, huh?
你第一次看到杀人?
Leave her alone
放过她
You think I'm a monster? That I would kill this man?
我杀死他 你认为我是怪物
Somebody's son? Somebody's father?
因为他是别人的儿子 别人的父亲
I am somebody's son, too
我也是别人的儿子
I have three small children
我有三个小孩
Does that surprise you?
你很惊讶吗?
- Tell her to answer, - Leave her alone!
- 叫她回答 - 放过她吧
Shut up!
闭嘴
Why did you kill him?
你为什么杀他?
Because I believe
因为我相信
And when I shoot this man, I know in that instant
当我杀死这个人 我知道在这一瞬间
how deep was my belief
他将确知我的决心
That I would turn my back on God Himself, for Mother Russia
我愿意为苏俄祖国背叛上帝
My doubts, my fears, My own private morality
我的疑虑 恐惧 道德观念
for this love, Can all behind
为了祖国全都可以抛在脑后
You know, your father, he has also killed
你父亲也杀过人 他是坏人吗?
- Is he a bad man? - That's not true
- 不是 - 那不真的
Why?
为什么?
Because he does it in a tuxedo with a telephone call and a smart bomb?
因为他西装毕挺 用导弹杀人吗?
You are a monster, And my father is a great man
你是个怪物我父亲很伟大
You're nothing like my father
你根本就比不上他
What's the goddamn number?
电话号码是多少?
- What city please? - Washington D C, the White House
- 查号台您好 - 华府白宫
- Just a moment, Here's the number, - Can you connect me to that number?
- 稍候 这是号码 - 你能帮我接吗?
- There's a connect fee of one dollar, - Fine
- 可以收费一元 - 好
White House switchboard, How may I direct your call?
白宫总机 请问您找哪里?
All right, listen, Listen carefully
你要听好
This is an emergency call from "Air Force One,"
这是紧急状况
This is the president, Connect me to the vice president
我是总统 帮我接副总统
Who did you say is calling?
你说你是谁?
- This is the president! - Right, and I'm the First Lady
- 我是总统 - 是呀 那我就是第一夫人
Don't cut me off, This is an emergency
别挂断这是急事
The president doesn't call this particular number, so whoever you are. . .
先生 总统不会打这电话
Trace the call, Follow your standard security procedure
你尽管按照标准的保安程序
Trace the goddamn call!
追查这通电话来源
Okay, sir, You want to make a federal case out of this, fine by me!
好吧 你想把事情闹大随你便
Hello, Anyone there?
喂 有人在吗?
Don't move
别动
- I traced the call, sir, - Give me the gun
- 我正在追查 - 把枪给我
- Are you there? - Slowly
- 你还在吗? - 慢慢来
Oh, my God!
我的天
I'll put you right through, Mr.President
我马上帮你接总统先生
The switchboard has a call from someone claiming to be the president
总机接到自称是总统的电话
She traced it back to the White House satellite account
她追查到白宫卫星帐号
The caller's gone, but the line is still active
对方不在 可是没挂断
Put it through
接过来
Listen to me, Listen to me, You know who I am
听我说听好 你知道我是谁
I'm the president of the United States
我是美国总统
- Yes! - Quiet!
- 好 - 安静的!
Don't think that means I don't shoot you
我一样能杀你
Put your hands behind your head and move
手放在头上快点
This is your lucky day
今天是你幸运日
What more can my people do? Tell the F-15s to fire at the plane?
他们能怎样? 命令战机开火吗?
Even if they tried, we're equipped with tactical countermeasures
就算开火 空军一号也有反制能力
- He's talking to us, - What do you mean?
- 他对我们说话 - 那是什么意思?
I just want you to feel secure, That way no one will get hurt
我只是想让你感到安全 这样没有人会受到伤害
The computer will fly circles around any missile they fire at us
电脑会自动闪躲飞弹
- And no hit, just a shock wave, - He's telling us what to do
- 我们只会受到震动 - 他在教我们怎么做
Believe me, all that would happen is that we'd get knocked off our feet
相信我 这一切会发生我们希望得到拖我们脚下
- That's all! - Shut up!
- 这是全部 - 给我闭嘴
President has been hijacked
总统已被劫持了
- If we're going to act, we must act now, - It's too risky
- 我们得马上行动 - 太危险了
The president is up there with a gun to his head
有人拿枪指着总统
He's asking us to do that to "Air Force One"?
他要我们向他发射飞弹?
He's not asking
这不是要求
Your commander in chief has issued a direct order, Do it!
这是最高指挥官的命令 快去做
Are you sure that's what you want me to do?
你真的要我这么做?
You heard me, Let's pray it works the way it's supposed to
你听到了希望这么做有用
Boys, give me room, I've been ordered to fire on "Air Force One,"
大伙让开 我奉命向空军一号开火
I'm in position, Missiles are armed
我已就位飞弹已备妥
The target is acquired, I have a good lock
锁定目标 目标很清楚
God, I hope this works, Fox Three
希望能成功 发射
The abolition of automatic driving
"取消自动驾驶"
"Incoming missile
"飞弹来袭"
How's going on?
怎么回事?
Yankees to fire
美国佬向我们开火
I lost control
我失去控制
Computer to take over the driving
电脑接管驾驶
"Ready to shoot bait"
"准备射出诱饵"
"Injection bait"
"射出诱饵"
They are crazy?
他们疯了吗?
This is Marshall
我是马歇尔
- Anyone there? - We're here, Mr.President
- 有人在吗? - 我们都在总统先生
Where's my family? Are they safe?
我的家人安全吗?
The terrorists claim they're holding them, We can't confirm
对方声称在他们手上 我们无法确认
Who are they? What do they want?
对方是谁? 有何目的?
They're Russian ultranationalist radicals, They want General Radek, released from prison
苏俄极端份子 他们要交换拉狄克
General Radek
拉狄克
- What are our tactical options? - We're working on that
- 我们有什么办法对付? - 我们正在想办法
- But the bastards have us in a corner, - There is no rescue attempt?
- 不过他们的手段狠毒 - 你们没尝试救援行动?
I ruled out a midair rescue
空中救援太困难
We can do nothing while the plane's in the air
在半空中行不通
We gotta get this plane on the ground
飞机得降落
Take me off the speakerphone
别用免持听筒
- Where's Bennett? - Mr.President
- 班奈特呢? - 总统先生
We cannot release Radek
绝对不能释放拉狄克
They're gonna shoot a hostage every half hour until we do
对方每半小时处决一名人质
I don't want a plane full of dead people
我不想让大家送死
They shot Jack Doherty
杰克・达赫迪被杀死啦
Christ!
老天
We can't give in to their demands, It won't end there
你不能让步否则没完没了
If you die in the plane, does it end there?
你死了就能了结吗?
We've got a job to do, whatever the cost
不管付出什么代价 我们都得尽职
Catherine
凯瑟琳
A piece of biscuit to the rats
给老鼠一块饼干
He'll want a glass of milk
它就会想要喝牛奶
We gotta get this plane on the ground
我们得逼飞机降落
Robards Rloff come back?
巴兹洛夫回来了吗?
no
没有
Get the plane on the ground
让飞机降落地面
Below us in the shelter
下面的人在躲避着我们
I soon lost patience
我就快失去耐性
"Fuel-control system"
"燃油控制系统"
I would like to invite you to join us
我想请你加入我们
It is starting to feel a little empty up here
这地方有点空荡
Sit down, Please
请你坐下来
"Fuel-control"
"燃油控制"
Come
过来
Tell me your name again, for the record
说出你的姓名 让大家知道
Melanie, Melanie Mitchell
梅兰妮 梅兰妮・米契
You travel often, with the President?
你常和总统一起飞行?
Yes
是的
So you know everyone on the plane?
你认识机上每一个人
I bet they like you, huh? You're a nice person, yes?
你的人很好 他们都喜欢你?
I guess so
我猜是吧
You tremble
你在发抖
Why are you afraid?
你为什么害怕?
Because I don't wanna die
因为我不想死
Tell me, what am I doing at this moment?
告诉我 我正在做什么?
You're pointing a gun at me
你拿枪指着我
Thank you, Melanie
谢谢你
This is to the secret service agent in the baggage deck
行李舱的特勤人员听好
I will count to ten
我数到十
And if you do not surrender, this nice woman will die
你不投降 这位小姐就会死
One
一
- Please don't, - Two
- 不要这样 - 二
- Don't do this! - Three
- 别这么做 - 三
- Let me talk to him! - Four
- 让我跟他说 - 四
- I beg you, please, - Five
- 求求你 - 五
Let me talk to the agent
让我和他说话
- Six, - He might listen to me
- 六 - 他会听我的话
Seven
七
- I beg you, don't do this, - Eight
- 我求求你别下手 - 八
- Don't do this, please! - Nine!
- 请你住手 - 九
No
不
Oh, God
我的天啊
Let's think about that one for a moment
大家好好地想一想
And then we'll start again
然后再重新开始
Next time, I'll choose someone more important
下次 我会挑更重要的人下手
I know what you think the First Lady
我知道你在想什么 第一夫人
You want me dead, It may come to that
你要我死也许我会死
In a war, people die
在战时人都会死
This isn't war!
这不是战争
You just murdered an unarmed woman
你杀死手无寸铁的女人
You, who murdered 100, 000 Iraqis to save a nickel on a gallon of gas
你们为了省油钱 杀死十万名伊拉克人
are going to lecture me about the rules of war?
你还敢教训我战争的道理?
Don't!
给我住嘴
Mr.President, how can I help you?
总统先生 我该怎么帮你?
Chief, you can help me dump some fuel
你得帮我倾泄燃油
Who's down there in the baggage deck?
行李舱有什么人?
- It's a secret service agent, Who? - We have no idea
- 他说是特勤人员 是谁? - 我不知道
Melanie was shot because one of your men wouldn't show himself
你的手下不肯现身 把梅兰妮害死
I want to know who he is,
我要知道这孬种是谁
Sir, it's someone smart enough to know
这个人知道
if you're hunting with one bullet, you wait for a clean shot
他得等待机会一举成功
What are you saying?
什么意思?
Whoever that is down there, he may be our only hope
不管他是谁 他是我们唯一的希望
Our only hope is that Washington complies with this bastard
我们唯一的希望是 华府答应对方的要求
Because any minute now another one of us is dead
因为另一个人马上就会死
And you know what?
知道吗?
I'm afraid it might be me
我很怕会是我
- Sir, do you see the maintenance panel? - I see it
- 看到维修面板吗? - 看到
Pop it open, There should be a red switch, Toggle it up
打开来扳上红色开关
Hang on
等等
We got some indicator lights here
有些指示灯
To dump the fuel, you have to close the circuit for the pump
切断泵的电流就能泄油
There's no switch, so you'll have to cross the wires
没有开关 你得接电线
- Open the fuel control door, - Hang on
- 打开燃油控制门 - 接着
There should be five of them
应该有五根电线看到吗?
- Do you see them, sir? - I see them, Yeah
- 你看到了吗? - 看到了
Jesus, There's a lot of goddamn wires, All right, wait a second
天哪 电线真多好了 接下来
We got five, Green, yellow, red, white and blue
有五根 绿 黄 红 白和蓝
Let me double-check
等等让我查一下
Come on, For Christ's sake, hurry up
拜托你快点
Get the wrong wire, you'll cut the engine feeds
接错电线 切断引擎
The plane will crash
就会坠机
Then we don't want to get the wrong wire, do we?
那就别接错电线
Cut the green wire
先切断绿色电线
green wire
绿色电线
Cut
切断了
- Then, cross the. . . - With the. . . With the what?
- 再把这条线缠在... - 缠在哪儿? 喂?
Hello? Cross it with the what? Say again
再说一遍 把绿色电线缠在...
Cross the green wire with the. . .
绿线交叉的. . .
"Run out of battery"
"电池耗尽"
For Christ's sake!
老天爷
Wait, green, yellow
绿 黄红白蓝缠住绿线
I'm counting on you, red, white and blue
全靠你了 国旗色
Sirs, it looks like "Air Force One" is losing fuel
看来空军一号正在漏油
We out the oil
我们在漏油
out oil
"漏油"
It was hands-feet below
有人在下面动手脚
Damn
该死
I'm go down
我要下去
With Shag band
带沙格去
To see other people on the shoot
看到别人就格杀勿论
ok
知道
Quick give me magazine
快给我弹匣
Are you ok?
你没事吧?
Shag band
沙格? 科契?
What's happened?
怎么回事?
he's ded help me
他死了帮帮忙
Madam Vice President
副总统
the time has come for you to demonstrate your good faith
现在轮到你说话算话
I've been reading through your press kit
我看过资料
I understand "Air Force One" is able to refuel in midair
空军一号能在半空加油
We need fuel, And we need it now
我们马上就得加油
I'm sure we can come to some sort of arrangement
我应该可以安排
If you'll land the plane, we'll trade fuel for hostages
请你降落 用人质交换燃油
This is bullshit! It's simple physics
想都别想这很简单
Without fuel, the plane crashes, Everybody dies
没有油 就坠机 大家一起死
We're trying to do everything that we can
我们正在想办法
Tell me what I want to hear
你不乖乖照办
or I will execute a member of the senior staff
我就开始杀人
and continue killing one hostage every minute
每分钟处决一人
until the plane crash or refueling plane arrive!
直到我们坠机 或是输油机到达
What do you say?
你怎么说?
Fuel's on its way
燃油马上到
Thank you
谢谢你
They will help us fuel
他们会替我们加油
Go
上吧
It's all right?
没事吧?
Yeh
没事
Move
快走
- Jim, what are you doing here? - I never left
- 你来这儿干嘛? - 我没离开
Djibouti
吉布
Watch the door
守住门
Where's my family?
我的家人呢?
Another part of the plane, We haven't seen them
她们被带到别的地方
We got weapons now, We should try to retake the plane
我们应该试着抢回飞机
Not while they've got Grace and Alice, I can't take that chance
格蕾丝和爱丽丝在他们手上 我不能冒险
What about trying to disable the plane and force them to land?
能不能破坏机件 逼他们降落?
I tried, I dumped some fuel, Now they're gonna refuel us in midair
我泄过油 他们要在空中加油
A refueling tanker? Jesus! Sir?
加油? 天哪长官
- There may be a way to get people off, - What do you mean?
- 也许我们有办法逃走 - 怎么说?
We have emergency parachutes in the tail cone, but we're too high
机尾有降落伞 目前高度太高
If we could get a message to the refueling tanker
只要通知输油机
get him to drop to 15, 000 feet, we could jump
降到一万五千尺就能跳机
They've disabled the phones, They control the radios
他们切断电话 控制无线电
- Mr.President? Sir? The fax machines, - The phone lines are out
- 总统先生? 长官 传真机? - 电话都被切断
No, Voice lines and faxes are on two different systems of encryption
电话和传真系统不同
If you disable one, it'd be easy to overlook the other
切断一个 很容易忽略另一个
If this works, you get to be postmaster general, Come with me
要是成功 你就当邮政局长 跟我来
- Get these people ready, - Yes, Remember
- 让大家准备好 - 好的 记得
15,000 feet and 200 knots, Otherwise it's suicide
一万五千尺 两百节 否则就是自杀
You'll need this
你需要这个
Good luck, people
祝好运
I need a pen
我要一支笔
- Where are we sending it? - Situation Room
- 传到哪里? - 战略室
It makes me so proud that you stuck with us
你为了我们留下来 我感到很光荣
- Thanks, - Whatever happens
- 谢了 - 不管发生什么事
Yes!
快点
Madam Vice President, the attorney general is here
副总统 司法部长来了
- Thank you for coming, Andrew, - Good that you're here
- 谢谢你赶来 - 你来了就好
You want my interpretation of what the Constitution says about the situation?
你们要知道宪法怎么规定
Yes, Andrew, my understanding is
据我所知
that if the president is out of contact in a military situation
总统因战事失踪
the secretary of defense is in charge as second in command
应该由国防部长接管
- Yes, of course, - Good, Then that settles it
- 当然 - 很好 这就没问题
It doesn't settle it at all
问题可大了
The president is not merely out of contact, He is also under duress
总统不只是失踪 他还受到胁迫
His family is held hostage, possibly himself a hostage
他的家属是人质 他自己也可能是
It creates an incapacity to discharge the office under the 25th amendment
根据宪法第25条修正法案
Surely just as if he'd had a stroke
他就跟中风一样 无法行使职权
I think the president would dispute that any incapacity exists
我看总统会否认这一点
It exists if a majority of the cabinet, including yourself, says it exists
只要多数阁员 和你有共识就行
The president may be alive, but he may not be the president
总统也许还活着 他可能无法行使职权
- Madam Vice President? I think you need to see this, - This is CNN breaking news
- 副总统请你来看看 - CNN新闻
We interrupt programming to bring you this breaking news bulletin
我们中断节目带来新闻特报
CNN has received unconfirmed reports, that "Air Force One"has crashed
未经证实的消息指出 空军一号已经坠机
- Oh, my God! How did they get that? - I don't know
- 哦天哪! 他们怎么做到的? - 我不知道
The aircraft was en route from Moscow when it began its Mayday hail
总统专机飞离莫斯科后求救
I repeat, We have unconfirmed reports
我重复 消息指出...
Call the press room, We have to issue a statement
通知新闻室 我们得发表声明
that the president's plane has crashed in Eastern Europe
总统的飞机已经坠毁在东欧
. . . Then reportedly forced to land Air Force One is not
...随后据说 空军一号迫降不成
- Has "Air Force One" crashed? - That is a rumor
- 空军一号坠机了吗? - 那只是谣言
- Where'd the story come from? - I don't know where it came from
- 怎么开始的? - 不知道
Listen, I cannot confirm anything, at this point
听好 目前我无法确定
Ladies and gentlemen, I have a statement
各位 我要发表声明
The president's plane,"Air Force One," has been hijacked
总统专机 空军一号遭到劫机
Please, Ladies and gentlemen, please let me finish
各位 请让我说完
For security reasons, I cannot divulge
为了安全理由
the identity of the hijackers or who was on board the plane
我不能透露劫机者 和人质身分
But I'm here to assure the American people
不过我向美国人民保证
that we are doing everything we can to resolve the situation
我们正在尽全力解决此事
For the safety of all the people on the plane
为了人质的安全 我不能多说
I cannot tell you any more than I have, and I'm sure you understand that
你们一定能了解
Is James Marshall still the president?
詹姆斯・马歇尔还是总统吗?
I'm coordinating with the National Security Council
我正在和
pending the president's return
国家安全委员会协调
And, yes, James Marshall is still the president
詹姆斯・马歇尔仍然是总统
At this time. . .
目前...
At this time, I would like to ask all Americans
目前 我想请美国人民
to pray for the safety of everyone on board "Air Force One,"
祈祷空军一号上的人质安全
Thank you
谢谢
The president
总统
In his speech, Vice-President
副总统在发言
Where is the president?
总统在哪里?
The following okay?
下面没事吧?
Nothing
没事
Come, air refueling aircraft to the
快来 空中加油机到了
Folks, listen up, This is your main rip cord
大伙听好 这是主拉环
As soon as you clear the plane, give it a yank
一跳出去就用力拉
If your chute doesn't open, this is your reserve chute, Pull it down, Clear?
主伞没打开 就拉下备用伞 懂吗?
"30, 000- foot high"
"高度三万尺"
"Air Force One,"do you read?
空军一号收到吗?
Yes, we read, Go ahead
收到了 请说
"Air Force One," this is "Extender 1- 0,"
这是输油机 我们奉命来加油
- We have been instructed to refuel you, - Go ahead
- 我们已接到指示要加油给你 - 来吧
Drop to 15, 000 feet and slow to 200 knots
降到一万五千尺 减速到两百节
Acknowledged, Two hundred
收到 两百节
- They got it! - They got the fax
- 他们收到了 - 他们收到传真了
Sir, your chute
长官 你的降落伞
- Please, sir, - I'm not leaving without my family
- 求求你长官 - 我不能丢下家人
Okay,"Air Force One," you need to open your receptacle door
可以了 空军一号 打开燃油门
Pull the yellow lever on the upper control panel
拉下黄色开关
Done
好了
Go ahead and close distance nice and easy
拉近距离慢慢来
Almost there
快到了
- Where are your chutes? - We stay with the president, sir
- 你们的降落伞呢? - 我们和总统留下来
Thank you
谢谢你们
All right, that's close enough, Here we go!
可以了 来吧
"Open the door jump"
"开启跳伞门"
Go! Go! Go! Go!
快点 快点
Go take a look at
快去看看
We got,
人质逃走了
so far 25 chutes
目前我看到...25个人
- I can't hold her, - What are you doing?
- 我失去控制 - 你在做什么
Break away! Break away!
空军一号 快飞走
Sir, take my hand!
抓住我的手
Everybody, break now!
大伙 快飞走
- Don't move! - Let me save him!
- 别动 - 让我救他
He's the president, for God's sake!
他是美国总统 去救他
Grab my hand!
抓住我的手
Major!
少校
I got you
我抓住你了
We catch the President
我们逮到总统
We've lost the tanker? What else?
失去输油机 还有呢?
- They're counting 32 survivors, - That means they still have hostages
- 只有32名生还者 - 机上还有人质
- What about the first family? - No word yet
- 第一家庭呢? - 还没有消息
Losing hostages will make the terrorists more desperate
失去人质会逼急对方
Madam Vice President, we've got "Air Force One" on the line
副总统 空军一号在线上
This is Vice President Bennett, We're listening
我是副总统 我们在听
I now hold hostage, the president of the United States of America
现在美国总统在我手上
Soon we shall enter the sovereign airspace of Kazakhstan
我们很快就进入哈萨克斯坦领空
You will cease your military escort at the border
你们必须把战机叫回去
If you violate our airspace, I will execute a member of the first family
否则我就杀 第一家庭其中一人
Tell our fighters to back off
通知战机撤退
Get me Ops
帮我接指挥中心
You said a presidential incapacity could be declared by a cabinet majority
你说多数阁员 能宣布总统无权
- Would you sign it? - Under the circumstances
- 你肯签名吗? - 我别无选择
See who else would
去问还有谁肯
Move! Come on, move!
快点快走
Fast! Move! Quick! Right here
快 走 快 走这边
Dad
爸
- It'll be all right, - I know
- 不会有事的 - 我知道
You've been very busy downstairs, Haven't you?
你在下面挺忙的对吧?
Killing my men
你杀死我的手下
Stop
住手
You don't wanna do that
你最好别杀我
I'm what you came for, Don't forget that
别忘了你来的目的
Then I kill them, Or just one
那我就杀她们 随便你挑一个
You pick
挑呀
That's what you do in the White House, You play God
你在白宫不都是扮演上帝?
Go ahead, Which one lives?
快挑呀谁能活命?
I love you
我爱你
Go ahead
快呀
You're not here for this, You want something
你不是来打我 你另有目的
- What is it? - Radek
- 什么目的? - 拉狄克
- How can I do that? I can't, - Then you die, the three of you
- 我办不到 - 那我就杀死你们
I'll do anything to save my family, Don't ask something I can't give!
我愿意为她们死 这件事我办不到
The most powerful man on the earth, Suddenly, there are things you can't do
世界最有权力的人 也有办不到的事?
This is very curious, Stop with your fucking lies!
真好笑 别再骗人了
sotp
住手
- Petrov will never give up Radek, - Petrov is a dog
- 帕特罗夫不会放走拉狄克 - 帕特罗夫是条走狗
He does what you tell him
他听你的话
Tell him to do this
叫他乖乖照办
Petrov used me, I just wanted to stop the bloodshed
他利用我 我只想阻止屠杀
He wanted a personal victory, Petrov hates Radek
他却想报私仇他痛恨拉狄克
Of course he hates Radek, Radek is everything he is not
当然他比不上拉狄克
A great man, a strong man
拉狄克是坚强的伟人
Are you saying, he would refuse you?
你是说 帕特罗夫敢拒绝你?
You'd be playing right into his hands, Are you an idiot?
别傻了你这么做正合他意
You'd make him into a hero, The man who stopped the terrorists
他会成为 抵抗恐怖份子的英雄
Or better yet, the man who stopped me
更好的是 他能反对我
You talk as if you have nothing to do with this
你装得跟这件事毫无关系
This is all your doing
这全是你的错
This infection you call freedom, Without meaning, without purpose
你们所谓的自由毫无意义
You have given my country, to gangsters and prostitutes
你让俄国人沦为黑道和妓女
You have taken everything from us
你剥夺我们所有的尊严
There is nothing left
你让我们一无所有
Call him
打电话给他
No No
不不
Stop, d'not hurt her
住手 别伤害她
Sit!
坐下来
- No, - I have no choice
- 不 - 我别无选择
- You have the choice, - Leave her alone, It's between us
- 你有所选择 - 别伤害 她这是我们的事
You lose a child, it hollows you out
当你失去孩子 将痛不欲生
We're soldiers, You take my life
我们是军人 要杀就杀我
Have you no honor?
难道你没有荣誉感?
- I'll count to five, - No!
- 我数到五 - 不
- It's gonna be all right, honey, - One
- 没关系的 - 一
- It's gonna be all right, - Two
- 别怕 - 二
I'll do it
我愿意
You just leave my family alone
放过我的家人
Leave 'em alone
放过她们
Executive President of the United States
长官 美国总统
Mr.President!
总统先生
We just got an intercept
我们拦截到电话
The president called Petrov and asked him to release Radek
总统请帕特罗夫释放拉狄克
- He can't do that! - He must have no choice
- 他不能这么做 - 他别无选择
We have a choice
我们有所选择
I have the signatures of the cabinet attesting to the president's incapacity
多数阁员同意总统失去能力
- Sign it and you can overrule him, - No, I won't do that
- 只要你签名就成立 - 不 我办不到
The United States does not negotiate with terrorists
美国不和恐怖份子谈判
It's been our principle for 25 years, You can't give in to them now
这是25年来的政策 现在不能让步
It'll be open season on the United States, Many more will die
否则美国将饱受胁迫 损失人命
Jim isn't making this decision as president, but as a husband and father
他不是以总统身分做决定 而是以丈夫父亲的身分
History will judge you by what you do right now, For God's sake, sign it
历史将对你做评断 快签吧
No
不
You have been released
你被释放了
I can now confirm that General Radek is in the process of being released
我现在确认拉狄克将军正被释放
I repeat, General Radek is now being released
重复 拉狄克将军正被释放
Yes, yes, General Radek has been released
是啊 是啊 拉狄克将军已被释放
It is confirmed
证实了
They are releasing the general
他们正在释放将军
Now what?
现在呢?
Now we return to our homeland
我们回到祖国
where Radek will decide how best to use you
让拉狄克决定该怎么利用你
now that we know you are willing, to negotiate
现在我们知道你 愿意谈判
Our nation needs so many things
祖国需要很多东西
- You said you were gonna release us, - Forgive me, I lied
- 你说你会放我们走 - 原谅我我说谎
Listen
你们听
Jim
吉姆
Dad
爸
- Sir, are you hit? - Stay with the major, honey
- 你中弹了吗? - 跟着少校
- Alice, get in the cockpit, - Lie down
- 留在驾驶舱 - 躺下来
Grace
格蕾丝
JIm
吉姆
- Let her go! - Not until Radek is safely away
- 放她走 - 我要等到拉狄克安全出狱
Call it off, Don't give up Radek
快取消命令 别放走拉狄克
If anything happens to the general, your wife will die!
要是将军出事 你老婆就没命
No, Jim
不吉姆
Comrades
同志们
To meet our general
我们来迎接将军
He will receive them at any time
他们随时会接到他
You hear that? It's almost over, Mr.President
听到吗? 就快结束了 总统先生
Drop the gun!
把枪放下
Put Down
放下来
You made one mistake when you killed my pilot, Mr.President
你犯了大错 你杀死驾驶员
No one left to fly the plane
没有人会开飞机
And no parachute
也没有降落伞
Whatever happens
不管怎样
you lose and I win
你输了我赢了
Get off my plane!
滚下我的飞机
You all right?
你没事吧?
General was about to bring out their
他们正要带将军出去
Go, Go! Call Petrov!
快去吧 通知帕特罗夫
Stop, do not move
站住 别动
They killed him, Mr.President
他们杀死他 总统先生
He almost got away, Did you hear me? Radek is dead
差点被他逃走 听到吗? 拉狄克死了
Yes! It's the president, We have retaken the plane!
那是总统 他夺回了空军一号
His situation?
他的情况如何?
Not good
不太好
- I don't suppose you know how to fly, - No, sir
- 你会开飞机吗? - 不会
- Come along, I'll need a copilot, - Yes, sir
- 跟我来我 需要副驾驶 - 好 先生
How long did you fly?
你有多久没开飞机?
25 years, I only had a small plane
25年我 只开过小飞机
Nothing like this
没开过这么大的喷射客机
- Anybody there? - We're here, sir
- 有人在吗? - 我们都在
You got somebody that can help me fly this?
谁能帮我开这玩意?
Sir, this is ColonelJackson, We need to get you out of hostile territory
我是杰克森上校 你得飞离敌方领空
- Good idea, Bob, - Look above the central video screen
- 好主意 - 请你看上方的荧幕
There's a series of L, E, D, numbers, One of them should read 1-1-0
有一排号码一组是110
- Got it, - That's your course heading
- 有 - 那是飞行方向
Just below, there's a knob surrounded by hash marks
下面 是一个有刻度的圆柄
Turn that knob counterclockwise to 290
逆时钟方向转到290
- We're turning, - Good
- 我正在转 - 好
- This will take you out of Kazakhstan, - We're gonna be okay
- 你正飞离哈萨克斯坦 - 真的还假的?
We can't land this plane on autopilot, so we'll need to go over a few things
你不能用自动驾驶降落 让我解释一下
Where's the nearest safe landing site?
最近的降落地点在哪里?
Incirlik, Turkey
土耳其 尹索利基地
- General Northwood, - Madam?
- 诺维将军 - 太太
What's that?
那是什么?
- That red dot represents MiGs, - On course to intercept "Air Force One,"
- 副总统 那代表米格战机 - 他们要拦截空军一号
Christ! They took off from Aktubinsk, The base commander there is loyal to Radek
忠于拉狄克的空军基地派来的
General, send our fighters into Kazakhstan
快派战机前往哈萨克斯坦
Order them to use any and all means to protect the president
叫他们尽全力保护总统
When you're on final approach, keep the throttles mid-range
操纵杆尽量保持在中间
- Mr.President, can you hear me? - Yes, Kathryn
- 总统先生你听到吗? - 听到
We're tracking six MiGs closing on your position, I'm sending in
六架米格战机正接近你
our F-15s to protect you
我们派出F15战机保护你
- Shit! - Did she say MiGs?
- 可恶 - 她说米格战机?
Yes, she said MiGs
没错
Get in that seat and put a seat belt on, We're having trouble
甜心系好安全带 有麻烦了
These MiGs get closer, I'm gonna have to maneuver this thing
米格机太接近 我得闪躲
How do I get it off autopilot?
怎么取消自动驾驶?
Push the button on the yoke by your left thumb
按下左拇指的按钮
I'll try a little right turn
我要试着右转
Keep your moves smooth and steady, It's all flying, Just step on the ball
试着稳住机身 只要好好开就行
That's right, Just like riding a bike
就像骑单车一样
Halo Flight, we are cleared to commit, bearing 0-9-0
准备进行拦截方位090
Jettison tanks and push it up
抛弃油箱全速前进
These MiGs, how far away are they?
米格机还有多远?
"Radar Lock"
"雷达锁定"
Never mind
算了
- One coming, Countermeasures activated, - Left turn
- 来了一架 启动反制行动 - 左转
Jesus Christ!
老天哪
- We need some help, - U,S, fighters, this is "Air Force One,"
- 我们需要救兵 - 这是空军一号
We are under attack, Where are you?
我们受到攻击 你们在哪儿?
This is Halo Flight closing on your position, ETA two minutes
这是光环分队 两分钟后到
We may not be here!
可能来不及了
We're hit!
我们中弹
Christ, We're on fire, We've got an engine on fire
老天起火了
- Number four engine is on fire, - Pull the fire handle overhead
- 四号引擎起火 - 拉下上方灭火开关
I got it
让我来
- We're rolling right, - Left rudder, You have to compensate
- 我们向右兜圈 - 用左舵 平衡方向
- Do I pull back on number one engine? - Negative, You'll slow down
- 我该熄掉一号引擎吗? - 不 你会减速 调整动力
How to adjust?
怎么调整?
- Knob, Aft pedestal, - Jesus Christ!
- 用后方的转钮 - 老天爷
We got a red light, Looks like we're losing fuel
在闪红灯 看来在漏油
Halo Flight
光晕航班
Everybody lock a bandit
每个人锁定一架敌机
Stand by for max range, And Fox Three!
进入最远射程发射
Kill one!
击落一架
Kill two! Four more bandits bearing 0-9-0, Halo Flight engage!
还剩四架敌机 准备迎敌
Ha, ha! Good guys are here
救兵来了
- Bug out west, We'll cover you, - You got it
- 向西飞 我们掩护你 - 没问题
- Sir, pull up! You got one on your tail, - Get him off my tail!
- 快拉高 机尾有敌机 - 把它射下来
Missile away
发射飞弹向左爬升
- Break left and climb! - Shit! Sir, we've lost countermeasures
- 我们失去反制能力 - 狗屎! 先生我们已经失去反制能力
This is "Halo 2," They've lost countermeasures, I'm going in
空军一号失去反制能力 我去拦截
Two's down! "Halo 2"is down!
光环二号坠机
"Air Force One," are you still with us?
空军一号你在吗?
Yes! We're still here
我们还在
Not so fast, you son of a bitch!
别想逃王八蛋
The last three MiGs are bugging out, sir
最后三架米格机逃走了
It's Safe
安全了
- Bob, are you still there? - Yes, sir
- 鲍勃 你还在吗? - 我还在
Got a little problem here, My rudder is sluggish
有个问题 方向舵不听使唤
Let me look
让我看看
Oh, man!
老天
Sir, you're torn up pretty bad
机身严重受损
Do you have any elevator control?
升降舵呢?
It's sluggish, too, And we're still losing fuel
也很慢 而且还在漏油
All right
好吧
We got a problem up here, Sirs,"Air Force One" is badly hit
问题大了 空军一号严重受损
With the damage, there's no way they can land
他们没办法成功降落
I'm sorry, sir
很遗憾
- Thanks for your help, - I'll stay on your wing, sir
- 谢谢你的帮助 - 我会陪着你飞
Take it straight and steady until we figure out what to do
继续想办法
Sir
长官
You did great
你表现得很好
They can't control the plane, Engines are failing and they're losing fuel
飞机失去控制引擎失效 而且在漏油
There must be something we can do to help them
一定有什么办法
- Is that our airstrip strike team? - Yeah, Why?
- 那是空中攻击小组吗? - 是的怎么样?
I just had a wild idea
我有个疯狂的点子
Time is critical, Start turning north
时间紧迫 向北飞等待指示
- You'll get more details en route, - Yes, sir
- 您将得更详细的途径 - 是的
Change of orders acknowledged
确定更改命令
Try to hold your heading, sir, They'll rejoin in about 25 minutes
继续飞行 25分钟后和他们会合
All right
好吧
- We know it's risky, - Understood, But we are all out of options
- 我们知道这是危险的 - 很冒险 不过我们别无选择
Yeah, baby?
是啊 孩子?
It'll be okay, Everything's gonna work
没关系一切都会没事
Concerned Americans have gathered at the White House
关切的美国人民守在白宫
to await word on the president and his family
等待总统的消息
But CNN has learned that "Air Force One"
CNN得知 空军一号严重受损
is severely crippled and virtually unlandable
根本无法降落
Sources report that the first family is still trapped on board
据报第一家庭被困在机上
And a daring midair rescue operation is said to be underway
危险的空中救援正在进行中
"Air Force One,"this is "Liberty 2-4" approaching on your left side
自由24号接近左方 收到吗?
- Do you read? - "Air Force One," Loud and clear
- 你看见了吗 - 空军一号 清楚得很
Gibbs, they're here, Get the door
他们来了快去开门
- We'll need 10, 000 feet and 200 knots, - We've got to get her slowed down
- 高度一万尺 速度两百节 - 减速吧
"Air Force One"and "Liberty 2-4," this is "AWACS Blue Star,"
空军一号 自由24号
We have you in radar contact
这是雷达机看到你们了
"Liberty 2-4," they're almost out of fuel
自由24号他们快没油了
Roger
收到
"Air Force One,"keep the wings level
空军一号你得保持这高度
If the engines fail, sacriice altitude to maintain airspeed
要是引擎失效 就保持速度
Ready!
去吧
Free on the 24th, the first person to go on
自由24号 第一人下去了
Back up, Easy
退后 小心点
"Air Force One,"come left, six
空军一号 向左六度
- How's my speed? - It's good, See if you can hold it
- 速度如何? - 一切都好尽量维持
A little more left, sir, Three, two, stop
再向左三 二度 好了
Take my arm! Pull me in!
抓住我 拉我进去
Come on! Come on!
快点 快点
Open I
解开我
Good
好了
"Liberty," locked in, Where's the president?
锁住了 总统呢?
Up in the cockpit
在驾驶舱
- We lost another engine, - "Liberty," we lost another engine
- 又失去一具引擎 - 我们又失去一具引擎
"Liberty 2- 4," Acknowledged
收到了
Sir, time to go
长官走吧
- Who's gonna fly the plane? - I'll take care of that, sir, Got it
- 谁来开飞机? - 我来开好了
Go!
快去
Ramp to pilot, Second P, J, 's on the way
第二名伞兵正过去
- Mr.President, this way! - My family first
- 总统先生 这里请 - 我的家人先走
- Sir, I have orders to take you off, - Them first
- 我奉命先救你 - 她们先去
"Blue Star,"the third parajumper is boarding "Air Force One,"
第三名伞兵登机
- Standing by for recovery, - Roger, Moving into receiver position
- 准备接收 - 收到 降到接收位置
- Dad? - You'll be all right, honey
- 爸 - 你不会有事的
- Promise? - Promise
- 你保证? - 我保证
Close your eyes
闭上眼睛
You can do it, Just hold on tight
你办得到抓紧了
Nothing would happen, do not worry
不会有事 别担心
She's okay
她不会有事
Dad
爸
- Hang on! - Ramp to pilot, We got her!
- 抓紧抓紧 - 呼叫机长救到她了
I'm right behind you
我在你后面
Hang on, Good
抓紧 好
- You're next, sir, - Him next, He's wounded
- 轮到你了 - 他受伤他先去
- You go, - Come on, Shep, Come on, pal
- 你先去... - 来吧
We've lost another engine
又失去一具引擎
You're sinking too fast, We only have time for one more retrieval
你下降太快 只能再接一人
We're passing 3, 000 feet, Impact in less than two minutes
低于三千尺 两分钟后坠机
Get the president out of there!
快把总统救走
Right here
这边
Easy there
那儿容易
He's on
好了
- Get your arms ready, It's time to go, - What about the other team?
- 绑上带子 该走了 - 其他人呢?
There's no time, I can only take one more
没时间了 我只能带走一人
No! We're all going!
不行我们都要走
That's impossible, sir, I have to take you
不可能 我得带你走
It's time to get you off this plane, Go, sir
总统先生 你该下机了
Go!
请你快去吧
Please go!
求求你去吧
It was you?
原来是你
- Give me the strap! - I trusted you with my life
- 把带子给我 - 我把性命交给你
The next president will be, soon to me
下任总统也会 快给我
We have to release the cable, We're descending from 1200 feet
低于一千二百尺 快解开缆绳
I'm getting off this plane!
我要下飞机
Seven hundred!
七百尺
Five hundred! We have to pull up!
五百尺一定要拉高
"Blue Star," "Air Force One"is down, I repeat,"Air Force One"is down
空军一号坠机 重复空军一号坠机
"Liberty 2-4," do you have the president?
自由24号 救回总统了吗?
Right, You can do it
调整姿势 你办得到
- "Liberty,"do you have the president? - Stand by
- 自由号 救回总统了吗? - 请待命
Fort hood, texas his
把他拉上来
Hang on!
撑着点
We got him!
他得救了
"Liberty 2-4"is changing call signs,"Liberty 2-4"is now
自由24号更改名称
"Air Force One"!
现在它是空军一号
Mr.President, welcome aboard, sir
总统先生 欢迎登机